# Joshua (En Young) Lai

# 21 Palmetto Drive Apt. #A, Alhambra, CA. 91801

Cell: (626) 617 – 2106 • Email: aces621@yahoo.com

#### **SUMMARY**

I am a devoted associate skilled to tackle complicated problems with positive attitudes and no bias when working with team members. Utilized and enhanced the skills and techniques developed over my career in performing various projects in a multi-tasking role functioning as Information Security Analyst, Software Configuration Manager and Software Release Engineer. The overall completed tasks from my expertise, abilities, dependability and accomplishments made me a valued asset. Obtained exceptional skills in the following areas:

ClearQuest	• Trac	PL/SQL Developer	Unix/Linux	• LDAP/ADAM
<ul> <li>Subversion</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>AirWatch</li> </ul>	• Toad	• Perl/C/C++	LDIFDE/CSVDE
<ul> <li>TortoiseSVN</li> </ul>	<ul> <li>Splunk</li> </ul>	Teradata	• Java	

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Smart and Final Stores - Commerce, CA.

2006 - Present

# <u>Information Security Analyst</u>

Even though my current title is Information Security Analyst, my daily duties are, but not limited to, performing software releases independently and in liaison with the development team, configuring source control elements in production and user environments on various platforms. One of my greatest accomplished challenges was configuring SVN control on a production's running application without any interruptions. I am now administering over forty source controlled repositories. Analyze reported security events using the Splunk Enterprise Security tool on a daily basis. When further security investigations are needed, I would use Lansweeper, Symantec Endpoint Protection Manager, Palo Alto Logs and TippingPoint SMS Clients. Also completed in the following:

- Released applications to production environments in a timely manner to meet company milestones according to the policy, processes and procedures.
- Resolved developer's issues with ClearQuest & Subversion tasks to provide smooth operations on projects.
- Created Subversion repositories for projects required by SOX Audit.
- Provided install logs to Auditors during Audit season.
- Created How To documents for developers including the Software Configuration Management Plan.
- Trained developers on how to use best practices for creating Subversion branches for releases.
- Trained developers on how to use commands and functions using the TortoiseSVN, SVN and ClearQuest tools.
- Stage and perform releases using the TortoiseSVN and SVN (In Unix/Linux Environments) tools.
- Performed Mobile .ipa releases using the AirWatch tool.
- Performed Database Object releases using custom scripts and the PL/SQL Developer tool.
- Created and modified custom scripts to execute and log the installation processes on the Linux/Unix environment.
- Implemented methods for production releases in order to ensure implementers use the approved software items for production release. E.g. Created SVN Tags for DB Release.
- Attend weekly Software Change Control Board meetings and has lead the meetings in the past when my manager could not attend.
- Created Splunk Reports and Dashboards for users.

# QA Analyst – CTFL

Performed tests on various applications built on various platforms, such as, Mobile Devices (iPhone & iPad), .NET, Oracle, UNIX including the Mainframe system. Worked closely with various development teams on major projects and determined which levels of test method to employ in order to meet the company's milestone and collecting required documents. Also completed in the following:

- Analyzed, tested, implemented, and improved software development process by utilizing accurate configuration items data in each of its releases; it reduced release cycle time by half of its original.
- Performed tests on financial systems with developers and users to meet the business requirements.
- Performed tests on the Mainframe system with the developer using Code Reviews and Unit Testing.
- Performed independent testing on the Portal using Test Cases provided by the developer using the Functional Area and Performance Testing methods to validate accuracy of the business sales reports.
- Performed tests on the Supply Chain/Store systems and hands on testing to meet the users and business needs.
- Performed tests on Mobile applications using the iPhone and iPad by ensuring the data displayed are accurate and viewable which provided users with confident when viewing sales reporting.
- Wrote queries to verify and compare data for tests using PL/SQL Developer, TOAD and Teradata tool, as a result, enhanced data integrity.

#### **QS** Coordinator

Utilized my problem solving skills to the extent in using the ClearQuest tool to manage Software Change Requests. The skills and knowledge that I have achieved from was the development life cycle and the release process with various IT development teams. Also completed in the following:

- Involved in all SQA activities to ensure all documents are provided and requirements meets the SQA Entrance and Exit Criteria.
- Administering and maintaining ClearQuest to accurately generate the current state of a bug fix/feature enhancement and the overall project evaluation for project managers/developers to better assist on their software development.
- Inherited responsibilities for all documentations on all Change Requests submitted to ClearQuest
- Made independent responsible mature decisions during critical times to meet the business needs
- Facilitated and generated reports for Change Management Control Board Meetings. Distributed the reports to the board which provided clear descriptions of the latest status and state of projects.

#### Access Request/LDAP Administrator

Ensure all requested access to applications meets the user's identity and business needs in a timely manner. Excel in team collaboration and solution brainstorming. Applying and maintaining a friendly service mentality is a must in order to satisfy all users' needs. The followings are additional information of my responsibilities and involvements:

- Utilized the company's API In House build Application called LDAP.
- Acquired the hands-on experience and knowledge working in a professional environment as a team member that allowed mental maturity and the highest respect for all aspects of the engineering field.
- Interacted with associates in all departments
- Constantly maintained a sturdy communication with Application Business Owners, Customers and Application Administrators
- Enforced all required policies to ensure all procedures meet auditing requirements
- Improved the Access Request Plans and Procedure documentation to clearly identify the Access Request's processes
- Involved in auditing reviews and provided all required documents
- Created Perl Scripts, Batch Files, LDIFDE & CSVDE to maintain the integrity of LDAP's data.
- Performed Quarterly and Semi-Annual internal audit reviews.

# Systempro Computer Inc. - City of Industry, CA

2004 - 2006

## Computer Technician

In this prominent diminutive company, I have enhanced my skills and knowledge of a simple computer. I have also assisted as a salesperson and a technician at most of the computer fair. This position requires a person with swift problem solving skills and must be versatile. The followings are the knowledge and skills that I have gained from and used for this company:

- Utilized my multitasking skills by building multiple computers while installing drivers and software on others
- Enhanced my skills and perception to a higher level of quality control
- Assembling a whole new robust computer from scratch
- Gained a better understanding of how does the computer hardware and software collaborated with each other
- Gained further knowledge of various computer part's features and functions
- Run tests on every new system to assure all drives are robust before releasing the system with a QA perspective
- Assisted on phone and human interaction with Tech Support when required
- Handled most of the Quality Control to insure a high quality computer system

# MODCOMP Inc - Ft. Lauderdale, FL

1999 - 2000

## Intern Software Engineer

Excel in team collaboration and solution brainstorming. Applied rigor and creativity that combines my knowledge that I've learned from school research; human-computer interaction, and graphic design to solve diverse GUI design issues.

- Utilized the company's API (Viewmax) to modernize the user interface
- Co-wrote programs and implemented them using HTML and JavaScript also assisted in minor Java Applications
- Implemented new GUI demos for both Pocket PC (using Web Clipping) and cellular phones (using WML and WMLScript) that enhanced salesperson to insure an error free environment when presenting the company's demo to vendors. Managed all phases of GUI for the interactive and transactional e-commerce site for the demo.
- Acquired the hands-on experience and knowledge working in a professional environment as a team member that allowed mental maturity and the highest respect for all aspects of the engineering field.

#### **EDUCATION**

B.S., Computer Engineering, Florida Atlantic University, Bacon Raton, FL

**December 14, 2001** 

## **CERTIFICATES AND TRAINING**

- Certificate for Introduction to Cyber Security 2015
- Certificate for Advanced Excel 2003 2011
- Certificate for Intermediate Excel 2003 2011
- Certified Tester, Foundation Level 2010